ferris.edu 2019-03-05

# Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy for the Ferris State website (ferris.edu)
Effective: March 1, 2017
Policy: 2017:08
This website (the “Site”) is owned and operated by Ferris State University (“Ferris State”, “Ferris”, “we”, or “us”),
and this Privacy Policy explains our collection, use, and disclosure practices regarding information that we collect
through the Site. Please review this Privacy Policy periodically as we may update it from time to time. Each time
you visit our Site or provide us with information, you are, by doing so, accepting the practices described in this Privacy
Policy at that time, and you acknowledge that by using the Site you are expressly and affirmatively consenting to our
use and disclosure of the information you provide in accordance with this Privacy Policy. We value the privacy of
our website visitors. We will collect and use your information only as explained in this Privacy Policy.
Summary
This section gives a brief overview of our data collection and use policies. Please see below for a more detailed
discussion of each topic.
We collect the following information through the Site:
       • Information that your browser routinely shares with websites.
       • Personal information that you provide on a voluntary basis.
Your information is used and disclosed for the following purposes:
       • To provide information regarding programs, events, or services that you request.
       • To register you for events or services that you request.
       • To provide you with information regarding our programs, services, products or events, or those of our
            agents and affiliated organizations, that you have expressed interest in or that we believe you may be
            interested in.
       • To help us improve our Site and better understand our Site’s users and their preferences.
       • To our contractors who provide supporting services so that they can access information needed for such
            services, but only on terms consistent with this policy.
       • To protect our business interests or the rights of others, when required by law, to cooperate with law
            enforcement.
The Site may use the following types of tracking technology:
       • Cookies, web beacons and similar technology tracks movement across our Site and keeps track of our
            registered users and their preferences.
       • Our current web analytics service is Google Analytics. To understand how Google Analytics collects
            and processes data, please visit www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/ .
Other details about our practices:
       • Although the Site may contain links to other websites not owned or operated by Ferris State or its
            affiliated organizations, this Privacy Policy applies only to those sites owned or operated by us or our
            affiliated organizations.
       • We use your personal information only for the purposes for which it is collected and consistent with this
            policy, and we retain your information as permitted by applicable law.
       • We do not intend to collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13.
       • We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time, but we will allow you to opt in to any retroactive
            material changes in how we use your personal information.
How we collect information
Personal information that you provide:
We collect personal information that you voluntarily provide to us when you use the Site or inquire about our
products and services, such as your name, email address, and mailing address. When we ask for your personal
information, it is so that we can provide a product or service to you and communicate with you about those products

and services. It will always be your choice whether to provide your personal information in order to take advantage
of the Site’s features. However, you may not be able to access certain portions or features of the Site, register for
certain events, or register to receive additional information about our programs and services without providing some
personal information.
Information provided by your web browser:
Like many other websites, we may collect and record data that your web browser routinely shares, such as your
internet protocol address, browser type, operating system, the website from which you came, and the pages on this
Site that you visit (collectively “Aggregate Information”). We will not try to associate any Aggregate Information
with any personal information that you provide to us. All Aggregate Information that is collected on the Site is
collected via Google Analytics. For more information about how Google Analytics collects and processes data,
please visit www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/.
What We Do With the Personal Information We Receive
We will generally use the information that we collect to help us operate the Site, to provide requested services, to
provide information about requested programs, and to help us understand our users and their preferences. The
following sections provide a more specific discussion of our uses and disclosures of information that we collect. We
will seek your consent before we use or disclose your personal information for any other purposes.
To register you for events or programs and to provide requested products and services:
We may use your information to provide you with the products and services that you request and to communicate
with you about events and programs that you have registered for on the Site. For example, when you register on the
Site for an event, we may use your contact information to send you communications regarding the event, or when
you request additional information about one of our programs or services, we will use your information to
communicate with you about that program or service.
To provide you with information about products or services that you may be interested in:
We may also use your information to provide you with information about our programs, services, products or events,
or those of our agents and affiliated organizations, that you have expressed interest in or that we believe you may be
interested in. However, you will always be free to opt-out of receiving such additional information if you choose.
Statistical analyses of the information:
We currently use Google Analytics to help us gather Aggregate Information. We may use this information to gain a
better understanding of our Site’s users and to improve our Site, our services, products, or program offerings, or our
student recruitment efforts. Depending on the type of browser and device that you use, you may have the ability to
control the type of information that Google Analytics uses.
Information shared with our business partners:
We may use business partners to help us design and operate the Site or provide other services to support the Site. For
example, we may hire a company to host the Site, run certain website applications, help us analyze the Aggregate
Information we collect from the Site, or improve the Site, or our products, services, and recruitment efforts. Unless
otherwise indicated on the Site, if we allow any these business partners to access the personal information that we
collect, it will be for limited purposes and in compliance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.
Law enforcement and legal actions:
We reserve the right to release your information without prior notice when we believe it is appropriate to prevent
fraud; to comply with law or to cooperate with law enforcement activity or other governmental request; to respond
to subpoenas, court orders or administrative agency requests for information; to enforce our policies; to protect the
rights, property and safety of our business and of others; or when required or otherwise permitted by law. For
example, we may share information with law enforcement if we suspect that someone is using or attempting to use
our Site for illegal reasons.

Use of Cookies and Similar Technology
We use cookies to keep track of the Site’s users and for their protection and convenience. A “cookie” is a small text
file containing alphanumeric characters that is stored on your computer and uniquely identifies your web browser.
Cookies allow us to, for example, authenticate users, determine if this is a user’s first visit to our Site, and remember
our user’s preferences. We may allow business partners, such as Google Analytics, who provide services to our Site
to place cookies on your computer that assist us in analyzing usage data. We do not allow these business partners to
collect your personal information from our website. Most Internet browsers enable you to erase cookies from your
computer hard drive, block all cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. Please be aware however,
that some of the Site’s features or services may not function properly without cookies. For more information about
how Google Analytics collects and processes data, please visit www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/.
How We Protect Your Personal Information
We use commercially reasonable means to protect the integrity of the Site and to limit access to the personal
information we collect through the Site, and to protect the security of information during transmission on the Site.
However, we cannot provide absolute assurances against, and will not be liable for, any breaches of data security or
confidentiality due to system failures or unauthorized access by third parties, or other causes beyond our reasonable
control.
Changes to This Policy
Our business and the laws that regulate us change from time to time, and we reserve the right to change this
policy. If we do change this policy, we will post the revised version on this Site. If we propose to change our policy
in a way that would permit us to make additional uses of the personal information that we had previously collected
about you, we will obtain your affirmative, express consent before using your information in a materially different
way.
Children
We will not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, please
do not try to register for an event, program, or service on the Site, and do not submit your personal information. If
you are a parent who believes that we have collected information about your child who is under the age of 13, please
contact us at TheodoreHalm@ferris.edu or at (231) 591-2331 with your child's name and address, and we will be
happy to delete the information we have about your child from our records and provide information in accordance
with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act.
Do-Not-Track
At this time the Site does not recognize automated browser signals regarding tracking mechanisms, which may
include “do not track” instructions. However, you can change your privacy preferences regarding the use of cookies
and similar technologies through your browser.
Contacting Us
Please contact us at TheodoreHalm@ferris.edu and let us know if you have any questions or comments about our
policies and practices.
12206841-2
